despegar.com 2017-07-26

# Privacy policy | International-English

Despegar.com (hereinafter, “Despegar” or “Us”) takes deep care of its users and it is committed to protect their confidentiality. To pursue such aim, Despegar has developed this privacy policy (hereinafter, the “Privacy Policy” or “Policy”) which describes Despegar’s policies and practices in connection with gathering, use and disclosure of personal information obtained from its users. When visiting, using and/or registering in this Website (hereinafter, the “Website”), you, as user (hereinafter, “You”), accept the practices described below. This Policy includes privacy policies of Despegar’s Website, in compliance with applicable laws.

**1.** **Information Gathered**

Despegar receives and storages personal information directly related to the services offered by Despegar and that users disclose when such users browse Despegar’s Website, use our on-line services, disclose such information by phone to our customer care center, take part in our promotions and offers, register as users, send emails, publish information in forums, chat groups or make comments interacting with the Website, use our application for mobile phones and tables (the “Application”) or when You contract or hire products or services with Us. The information gathered (hereinafter, the “Personal Information”) includes, among other information, full name, address, nationality, phone number, tax identification number, email address and, if you make a booking through our Website or our Application, your credit card information (for instance, credit card number, name of credit card holder and expiration date). We may also request information related to loyalty and frequent flyer programs. You may opt not to disclose such information to Us, but in general, certain information is required in order to purchase and perform transactions in our Website or our Application; therefore, if you choose not to disclose certain information You will not be able to do business with Us. In case You make a booking in the name of a third party, you must obtain first such third party’s consent before giving Us his/her Personal Information. Furthermore, Despegar may record or control for quality control and personnel training purposes, calls made to our customer care center. All calls recorded will be kept for a reasonable term and then will be deleted, at Despegar’s discretion.

**2.** **Other Information Gathered**

To the extent permitted by Law, Despegar may obtain your Personal Information and add it to the Personal Information disclosed by You to affiliate entities, business partners and other independent third parties, such as public databases, information gathered during a telephone conversation with the customer care center and/or interactive applications. You must take into account that all information gathered by Us may be combined with all Personal Information so that, for instance, we are able to adapt communications to your needs and develop new products or services that may be interesting for You. Any Personal Information obtained by Despegar through the means described herein will be handled in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy. As it is stated herein below, this Policy does not comprise practices from third parties from which we receive information.

**3.** **Registration Authorization and Treatment of Personal Information**

When visiting, using and/or registering in Despegar’s Website or the Application, You expressly authorize Despegar to record and treat all your Personal Information according to the following purposes, among other purposes: to carry out transactions commenced by You, to offer You products and services, to submit to You confirmations and updates related to your trip, to process invoices, to answer your questions and comments, to contact You for customer related purposes, to perform surveys, statistics or analysis on consumption habits or preferences, to inform You by email special offers and products and services related to trips that may result of your interest unless you do not want to receive such information (See herein below: “Opt Out Policy”). Furthermore, we use the information on credit cards (such as the name of the credit card holder, credit card number and expiration date) only to complete trip bookings made by You in our Website or on our Application, including the submission of data to final service renderers so as to manage your bookings and/or purchase requests. Likewise, You may opt for Despegar to remember certain data from your credit card and invoices which will automatically appear when entering to Despegar’s Website and/or the Application. When gathering Personal Information for advertising or direct sale and similar activities, such information will be treated pursuant to applicable laws.

**4.** **Storage and Transfer of Personal Information. Consent**

All Personal Information is gathered and stored in servers physically located in the United States. Despegar may change the location of such servers to any other country in the future and may store Personal Information in the United States or in any other country for back up purposes. You give your express consent so that Despegar may transfer your data to any country in the world.

When sending Personal Information to the Website and/or the Application, You authorize and give your express and informed consent so that, in accordance with applicable laws and with our Privacy Policy, Despegar may gather, use and store your Personal Information in order to (i) give and render the products and services requested by You; and (ii) send to You relevant customized information, including, without limitation, promotion of new products and services-.

In case of transfer of personal data, the addressee of such personal data will undertake the same obligations the responsible party transferring personal data has.

**5.** **Custody and Confidentiality of Personal Information**

The Personal Information will be treated with the degree of protection legally required so as to ensure confidentiality of such information and avoid any alteration, loss, or unauthorized treatment or access.

Despegar protects the Personal Information pursuant to security and confidentiality standards and procedures imposed by applicable laws. Despegar does not transfer, disclose or submit the Personal Information gathered to third parties other than the holders of such Personal Information and/or such third parties described herein. To such effect, this Website and the Application take the necessary measures to protect Users’ Personal Information.

**6.** **Access to Personal Information by Third Parties**

You grant your univocal consent so that Despegar may share relevant Personal Information of its users with suppliers in order to manage bookings and/or purchase requests, such as with airlines, hotels, vehicle rentals, wholesale companies and other product or services suppliers through our Website and/or our Application. Furthermore, you also grant your consent to share Personal Information with suppliers rendering services for Despegar, including credit cards, business analytics, customer care center, and marketing and fraud prevention. Moreover, we may also authorize service suppliers to collect Personal Information on our behalf, including, as it may be necessary to operate certain elements in our Website and/or our Application or to facilitate the submission of on line advertising tailored to your needs. Furthermore, Despegar may share Personal Information with business partners, together with whom we may offer products or services. Such suppliers and business partners are subject to confidentiality agreements that prohibit the unauthorized use or disclosure of Personal Information to which they have access. Despegar may share with them Personal Information in order to comply with applicable laws and cooperate with applicable authorities. Finally, Despegar may also share Personal Information with companies within Despegar.com group. Access to Personal Information by third parties will be subject to the Opt Out Policy described below.

**7.** **Opt Out Policy**

In case You perform transactions or register yourself as User in Despegar, You will have the option to receive promotions, messages or email alerts related to offers. You may change such option at any time through email configuration at Mi Despegar page. In addition, You will have the option to opt out the subscription upon reception of the message with every email.

**8.** **Access, Cancellation, Amendment and Opposition Rights related to Personal Information**

Users holders of Personal Information have rights to access, cancel and update their Personal Information and may oppose to the treatment given to such Personal Information. They also have the right to be informed of sessions carried out without cost at time intervals exceeding six months, and unless a legitimate interest is evidenced, they have the power to receive denunciations and claims filed in connection with the lack of compliance with rules on protection of personal data. 

Users are responsible for the accuracy, precision, effectiveness and authenticity of the Personal Information submitted and agree to keep such Personal Information updated. 

The above mentioned rights are exercised in writing by submitting the pertinent request by email to: [datospersonales@despegar.com](mailto:datospersonales@despegar.com). The request must include your full name and, if applicable, an instrument evidencing legal representation of the holder, simple copy of the identity document, email address and mailing address for the service of process and a telephone number. Furthermore the request must also include a detailed and accurate description of personal data in connection to which the right of access, amendment and cancellation is exercised and documents supporting such change.

Upon compliance with the above mentioned requirements and provided a request should be made, Despegar will inform You if your request is accepted or denied. 

Furthermore, You may access, update and correct your record information at any time in “Mi Perfil” at “Mi Despegar” in Despegar’s Website.

**9.** **Website Use**

It must be taken into consideration that upon access to Despegar’s Website, we automatically receive information on You and your computer. For instance, we receive information from cookies (see definition below) and web beacons (see definition below) regarding your browser and operating system, Internet pages and links visited by You, on your computer IP address and the website closed before accessing our Website. Despegar uses the information gathered mainly to improve your experience as User and improve our services.

At any time you may choose not to receive cookies by activating your web browser to reject cookies or to receive information before accepting then. You must also bear in mind that upon rejecting cookies You may not have access to several trip services and planning tools offered by this Website. Furthermore, in order to make transactions easier in our Website, You may choose that Despegar keep information on your credit cards. 

“ _Cookies”_ are text files automatically downloaded and stored in the hard disk of your computer when browsing certain Internet pages or portals, which allow saving certain data on your Internet activity. Cookies are used in order to know interests, behavior and demography of those visiting or using our Website and in this way, understand better their needs and interests and offer them a better service or give them related information. We will also use the information obtained with the cookies to analyze the pages browsed by the visitor or user, the searches performed, to improve our business initiatives and promotion, to show advertising or promotion, interest banners, customize contents, presentation and services.

“ _Web beacons”_ are images that may appear inserted in web pages and website and have similar purposes to that of cookies. In addition, a Web beacon is used to measures traffic patterns of users of one page to other in order to maximize flow traffic through the Web.

**10.** **Password and Access Protection**

Upon registration in Despegar, Despegar prompts You a user name and a password (i.e., access to a personal account in the Website known as “Mi Despegar”). Furthermore, Despegar Grants you access to “Mi Despegar” through your Facebook account, Google+ account or other social networks (hereinafter, the “Social Networks”) that in the future may also have access to “Mi Despegar”. If You loss control of your account or password to access to Social Networks You may loss control of your Personal Information and may be subject to legally valid transactions carried out under your name. Therefore, if for any reason whatsoever your password is compromised, You must forthwith: (i) change it, changing your registration information given to this Website and (ii) contact Us.

**11.** **External Links**

This Website may have links to other websites with their own privacy and confidentiality policies. Therefore, we recommend You to carefully read and analyze the confidentiality practices and policies of such websites whenever You visit them because this Privacy Policy does not cover third party policies or practices, including those that may disclose and/or share information with Despegar.

**12.** **Public Information**

It must be taken into consideration that when information is placed in the public area of this Website (including, without limitation, advertisement, chat groups, electronic photo albums and comments on products and services), such information is placed at the disposal of other members and users of the Website as well as the public in general; which exceeds the scope of control of Despegar. Please remember the above mentioned and be careful with the information you want to disclose.

**13.** **Party Responsible for the Protection of your Personal Information**

The party responsible for the database/file is Despegar.com USA, Inc. (1444 Biscayne Boulevard, Suite 221, Miami Florida).

**14.** **Amendments**

Despegar may change this Privacy Policy at any time in the future. Any change in the manner Despegar uses the Personal Information will be evidenced in future versions of this “Privacy Policy” and will be published in this page, therefore, You are advised to frequently review this Privacy Policy. 

**15.** **Contact Information**

In case of any questions in connection with this Privacy Policy, Despegar’s practices or transactions in Despegar’s page [www.despegar.com](http://www.despegar.com/), you may contact us in “Mi Despegar”.
